When you're creating Word documents, there
may be situations where you need to insert
images or charts to convey information or
to enhance the appearance of the document.
There is an opportunity for you to
practice this, and the first thing you
need to do is to download the two files
that we'll work through on this video.
The first one is called balloon.jpeg so
if you just click on that and then right
click on it and select, Save Picture As.
And then that will give
you the opportunity to save
it to a suitable location.
I've already saved that
into the WP2 folder.
And for the spreadsheet one,
it's slightly different.
So when you click on that, it
will give you the option at the
bottom to open, save, or cancel.
Or if you click on the
little arrow you can Save As.
So if I click Save As, again,
that brings me up with the
word processing unit folder.
And I will just save that in there and
that's done so I can then close that.
So when it comes to my Word document
that I want to insert the images
or the charts, bring that up.
And for this one, on this letter,
I'm going to insert an image
at the top of the document.
It's important to make sure that
you place the cursor in the right
position, because that is where
the actual image will be inserted.
Now, if I clicked, I insert the image
now, it would automatically place
it directly in front of the B Smith.
So I know there's a line space above,
so I'll just go there and I'm going to
go to insert and it's a picture from
this device and it is in my documents.
In the IT course and then
the word processing folder.
So if I now double click on
that, that will insert the image.
As you can see, the image is quite
large and needs to be formatted.
As mentioned earlier on this page
in the course, there are a variety
of tools and features that you
can use to format your picture.
This only appears when you have
the picture open or the picture
highlighted, as you can see
with the bars around the side.
If I clicked away from the picture,
it will go back to the home tab.
So to edit the picture, I need to
make sure that I have it selected
and the toolbar will change
to the picture formatting bar.
The only thing I need to do with the
picture is actually reduce the size.
And to keep the aspect ratio correct,
I will do that from the corner.
So if I select one of the corners
and just drag that in, as you can see
that is reducing the size, but also
keeping the aspect ratio correct.
So I will reduce that
too, I'm happy with that.
A bit more.
And that's it.
Now, as you can see, because I've
done that, the actual text has
gone off the bottom of the page.
So again, I do need to adjust
that a little bit more.
That's now fine.
Now that the image has been inserted into
the letter, it is time to insert the chart
. To access the chart, I will need to open
the spreadsheet file that I downloaded
from the vision2learn website, this was
saved in the word processing folder.
So if I navigate to that folder, and
it's indicated by an X for Excel.
If I double click on that, it will open
the spreadsheet containing the chart.
Don't worry too much about this as you
will be covering charts further down
the line in your spreadsheet unit.
The easiest way to transfer the chart
to the letter is to copy and paste.
So if I click on the chart and
highlight it and select the copy
icon, I can then go to the letter.
Make sure that cursor is exactly
where I wish the chart to be entered
and then select the paste icon.
This has inserted the
chart into the letter.
From here, you can carry out a
range of formatting techniques to
change the presentation, change
the layout, or change the colours
and change how it is displayed.
One of the beauties of having a chart
that is linked to an Excel document is
that if I go back to the chart and change
some of the data, if I go back to the
letter, this is automatically updated
within the chart within the letter.
So as long as you have those two
files working together, you will be
able to reuse the chart at a later
date and just change things around.